PARHAM ASHUR



QUANTITATIVE RESEARCH ANALYST, ECONOMIST

ABOUT

Energetic, ambitious, and a team player person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to undertake any task. Interdisciplinary research oriented mindset with knowledge of three languages. Over 5 years of experience in quantitative research analysis. Hands-on experience in a-to-z data analysis including cleaning, indicators, modeling, and visualization. Practical knowledge in a variety of econometrics modeling.

CONTACT



+33 7 67 20 95 95



parham.ashur@etu.univ-paris1.fr



Date of birth: March 1989



29 rue d'Ulm, Paris



parhamashur.com



∄ ■ Driver license

AWARDS AND HONORS

SKEMA Scholarship Full tuition waiver and living cost coverage (2017)

Ranked in the top 10% in the Bachelor Studies (2012)

Ranked in the top 0.3% in the National University Entrance Exam (2007)

FREELANCE PROJECTS Upwork

Data simulation - Mar. 2019

Social Media Data Analytics - Apr. 2019



EXPERIENCE

ECOLE NORMALE SUPÉRIEURE DEC 2018 - PRESENT PARIS, FRANCE

SKEMA BUSINESS SCHOOL SEP 2017 - AUG 2018 SOPHIA ANTIPOLIS, FRANCE

OILIFINA CONSULTING FIRM FEB 2017 - AUG 2017 PARIS, FRANCE

SAHAR OIL REFINERY CO. JUN 2014-FEB 2016 TEHRAN, IRAN



EDUCATION

PANTHÉON-SORBONNE UNIVERSITY UNIVERSITY OF PARIS-DESCARTES SEP 2018 - PRESENT PARIS, FRANCE

SKEMA BUSINESS SCHOOL UNIVERSITÉ COTE D'AZUR SEP 2017 - JUL 2018 SOPHIA ANTIPOLIS, FRANCE

UNIVERSITY OF AMSTERDAM SFP 2012 - AUG 2013 AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS

ALLAMEH TABATABAI UNIVERSITY SEP 2007 - AUG 2012 TEHRAN, IRAN

OUANTITATIVE ANALYST, INTERNSHIP

Designing and conducting experiments, working on data analytics and writing a paper, studying whether children adapt their syntactic predictions based on speaker identity.

OUANTITATIVE ANALYST, TEACHING ASSISTANT

Conducting research in the entrepreneurship domain, data analytics, and writing grant proposals. Teaching assistant for the Information System and Operation Seminars (450 students), and tutorial classes (40 students).

CONSULTANT

Pricing analyses, mentoring startups regarding business plans and business models. Lecturing in the Nano Match workshop on design thinking.

FEASIBILITY ANALYST

Conducting feasibility studies for several construction scenarios, corresponding with potential foreign investors,

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ECONOMICS AND PSYCHOLOGY

Courses in: Strategic Interactions, Econometrics, Research Methods, Applied Psychology, Social Psychology, and so forth.

MASTER OF RESEARCH, DIPLÔME UNIVERSITAIRE IN MANAGEMENT AND INNOVATION

Research on business pivoting in case of high-tech new ventures

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ECONOMICS

Master Thesis: "Does revealing information influence mobbing behavior" Supervisor: Gunul Dogan.

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ECONOMICS



TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- ◆ Econometrics tutor, SKEMA Business School 2017
- Business Mentor, Nano Match, Iran Nanotechnology Initiative Council (INIC) 2017
- Microeconomics and Macroeconomics tutor, Allameh Tabatabai University 2010 to 2012



SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- ♦ COMPUTER
 - Statistics: R and Stata
 - Graphics: familiar with Adobe Illustrator and Premiere
 - Programming: familiar with C and Python
 - · General: Office Suite, SharePoint
- ◆ LANGUAGES: English Fluent (TOEFL: 106, GRE), French B1 (Learning), Persian Native
- ♦ INTERESTS: Camping, reading, playing the piano, mountain trekking, skiing
- ♦ VOLUNTEER: UNICEF (2016-2017, France), Mahak Hospital and Rehabilitation Complex (2010-2011, Iran), Raad Rehabilitation Goodwill Complex NGO (2007-2009, Iran)